{
  "title": "Discrete_Mathematics - Discrete_Mathematics — Slot 29 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Discrete_Mathematics — Slot 29",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>The minimum number of edges in a connected cyclic graph on n vertices is: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1995)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>n-1</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>n</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>n+1</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>n</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2612/gate1995-1-25\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>The number of elements in the power set P(S) of the set \\(S=\\{\\{\\emptyset\\}, 1, \\{2, 3\\}\\}\\) is: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1995)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>2</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>4</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>8</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>8</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2607/gate1995-1-20\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>Let R be a symmetric and transitive relation on a set A. Then <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1995)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>R is reflexive and hence an equivalence relation</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>R is reflexive and hence a partial order</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>R is reflexive and hence not an equivalence relation</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2606/gate1995-1-19\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>The probability that a number selected at random between 100 and 999 (both inclusive) will not contain the digit 7 is: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1995)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(\\dfrac{16}{25}\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(\\left(\\dfrac{9}{10}\\right)^{3}\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(\\dfrac{27}{75}\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\dfrac{18}{25}\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\dfrac{18}{25}\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/780/gate1995-1-18\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>The number of substrings (of all lengths inclusive) that can be formed from a character string of length n is <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1994)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(n\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(n^2\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(\\frac{n(n-1)}{2}\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\frac{n(n+1)}{2}\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\frac{n(n+1)}{2}\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2458/gate1994-1-15\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>Some group (G, o) is known to be abelian. Then, which one of the following is true for G? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1994)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(g=g^{-1} \\text{ for every } g \\in G\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(g=g^2 \\text{ for every }g \\in G\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\((goh)^2 = g^2oh^2 \\text{ for every } g, h \\in G\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>G is of finite order</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>\\((goh)^2 = g^2oh^2 \\text{ for every } g, h \\in G\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2451/gate1994-1-10\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>The number of distinct simple graphs with up to three nodes is <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1994)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>15</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>10</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>7</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>9</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>7</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2443/gate1994-1-6-isro2008-29\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>Let A and B be any two arbitrary events, then, which one of the following is TRUE? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1994)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(P (A \\cap B) = P(A)P(B)\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(P (A \\cup B) = P(A)+P(B)\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(P (A \\mid B) = P(A \\cap B)P(B)\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(P (A \\cup B) \\leq P(A) + P(B)\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(P (A \\cup B) \\leq P(A) + P(B)\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2441/gate1994-1-4-isro2017-2\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>Let A and B be sets with cardinalities m and n respectively. The number of one-one mappings from A to B, when \\(m \\lt n\\), is <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1993)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(m^n\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(^nP_m\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(^mC_n\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(^nC_m\\)</p>",
            "<b>E.</b> <p>\\(^mP_n\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(^nP_m\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2304/gate1993-8-6\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>The less-than relation, \\(\\lt\\), on reals is <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1993)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>a partial ordering since it is asymmetric and reflexive</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>a partial ordering since it is antisymmetric and reflexive</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>not a partial ordering because it is not asymmetric and not reflexive</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>not a partial ordering because it is not antisymmetric and reflexive</p>",
            "<b>E.</b> <p>none of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>E.</b> <p>none of the above</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2303/gate1993-8-5\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>Let A be a finite set of size n. The number of elements in the power set of \\(A\\times A\\) is: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1993)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(2^{2^n}\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(2^{n^2}\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\((2^n)^2\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\((2^2)^n\\)</p>",
            "<b>E.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(2^{n^2}\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2302/gate1993-8-4\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>Let S be an infinite set and \\(S_1 \\dots , S_n\\) be sets such that \\(S_1 \\cup S_2 \\cup \\dots \\cup S_n = S\\). Then <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1993)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>at least one of the set \\(S_i\\) is a finite set</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>not more than one of the set \\(S_i\\) can be finite</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>at least one of the sets \\(S_i\\) is an infinite</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>not more than one of the sets \\(S_i\\) can be infinite</p>",
            "<b>E.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>at least one of the sets \\(S_i\\) is an infinite</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2301/gate1993-8-3\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>The proposition \\(p \\wedge (\\sim p \\vee q)\\) is: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1993)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>a tautology</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>logically equivalent to \\(p \\wedge q\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>logically equivalent to \\(p \\vee q\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>a contradiction</p>",
            "<b>E.</b> <p>none of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>logically equivalent to \\(p \\wedge q\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2300/gate1993-8-2\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>Consider a simple connected graph G with n vertices and n edges (n &gt; 2). Then, which of the following statements are true? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1993)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>G has no cycles</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>The graph obtained by removing any edge from G is not connected</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>G has at least one cycle</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>The graph obtained by removing any two edges from G is not connected</p>",
            "<b>E.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>G has at least one cycle</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2299/gate1993-8-1\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>How many undirected graphs (not necessarily connected) can be constructed out\nof a given set V={\\(V_{1},V_{2},.....,V_{n}\\)} of n vertices ? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2001)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(\\frac{n(n-1)}{2}\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(2^{n}\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>n!</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(2^{\\frac{n(n-1)}{2}}\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(2^{\\frac{n(n-1)}{2}}\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/733/gate2001-2-15#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}